中文字幕来源: R3-DVD 香港译本
本条字幕匹配109分钟的导演剪辑版
The Cell (2000)
For Director's Cut
109min
片名: 入 侵 脑 细 胞 港译: 移 魂 追 凶 台译: 死 亡 空 间
谢谢你把马借给我
Thank you for the horse.
- 你喜欢它吗?  - 它好美
- You liked him? - Oh, it's beautiful.
不过我还以为今天是去玩帆船
But I thought we were going sailing today.
你答应过的
You promised.
那艘太旧了
Well, that one's too old.
看  那艘就可以了
See, now? That'll do.
过来呀
Come on.
过来嘛  艾华
Come on, Mr. E.
- 船是破的  - 谁说的?
- It's broken. - Who says?
莫基洛
Mokelock.
艾华  你答应过不再提莫基洛的
Now, Edward, we agreed. No more Mokelock.
莫基洛就是那怪物
Mokelock is the bogeyman.
- 莫基洛想我留在这里  - 我们可以修好它的
- Mokelock wants me where I am. - We can fix it.
艾华
Edward.
唱"六便士歌"给我听听
Sing a song of sixpence.
一整袋的黑麦
CATHERINE: A pocket full of rye.
二十四只黑鸟
MIRIAM: Four and 20 blackbirds.
放在批里面烤
CATHERINE: Baked in a pie.
起床吧
MIRIAM: Rise and shine.
艾华看来不错
Mr. E is doing fine.
你俩有没有扬帆出海?
Did we go sailing?
几乎去了
Almost.
- 但莫基洛出现了  - 莫基洛是怪物
- Mokelock showed up. - Mokelock is the bogeyman.
他想我留在这里
Mokelock wants me where I am.
莫基洛真是烦死人
Mokelock is a pain in the ass.
- 他从哪里想出这个莫基洛?  - 鹅妈妈儿歌集
- HENRY: Where'd he get Mokelock again? - CATHERINE: Mother Goose.
- 亨利  - 贝里
- BARRY: Henry. - HENRY: Barry.
什么事  贝里?
What's the matter, Barry?
艾华的父母来了
Edward's, uh, parents are here.
(甘保中心)
他需要剪头发了
MRS. BAINES: He needs a haircut.
他很喜欢你来探他
CATHERINE: He loves it when you visit.
我丈夫怀疑这是不是真的
My husband wonders if that's true.
他想送艾华入医院
He wants to place Edward in a hospital.
对不起  嘉芙
I'm sorry, Catherine.
包先生
HENRY: Mr. Baines.
我已花了七年时间在这个计划上
I've been working on this project for seven years.
我知道  亨利  我知道
I know, Henry. I know.
请不要见怪
Please don't take offense, Dr. Kent.
- 你的工作很有价值  - 但你怀疑我
- Your work's invaluable to this company. - But you're not sure about me.
我们等进展等了十八个月
We've waited, uh, 18 months for signs of progress.
- 的确有进展啊  - 但没有证据
- There has been progress. - There's no proof, Catherine.
不怕得罪
With all due respect, Mr. Baines...
程序不是我设计的
...I'm not the one who designed the procedure.
我但愿这可以归功于我
I wish I could take credit for it, but I can't.
我只是被他们选中做一份工作
I was chosen to do a job. They picked me.
如果你认为有人会更合适
But if you think there's someone better...
或者有人对你儿子会更好
...or someone who's more devoted to your son, then--
没有人怀疑你的能力
No one's doubting your ability.
- 那为什么  - 没有证据  嘉芙
- What is it, then? - MR. BAINES: There's no proof, Catherine.
没有证据显示这个程序有用
There's no proof the procedure works.
你只是告诉我
All you're giving me is the belief...
你相信跟我儿子的接触不是
...that your interaction with my son is not a...
幻觉
...hallucination.
我还是回去工作好了  再见  包太
I better get back to work. Goodbye, Mrs. Baines.
- 谢谢你  - 谢谢  谢谢你  包先生
- Thank you. - Thank you. Thank you, Mr. Baines.
MR. BAINES: Come, shall we? Lucien.
我们走吧
- 幸好她崇拜你  - 因为他恨我
- Lucky she worships you. - Why? Because he hates me?
我不会说是"恨"  是不信任  很不喜欢
I wouldn't say "hates." Distrusts, dislikes immensely...
不想见到
...can't bear the sight of.
裁决是什么?
What's the verdict?
我们还有六个月
Well, we've got another six months...
贝里花了很多唇舌说服他
...and Barry had to push for that.
我想艾华倒过来进入我的世界  比以往更想
I wanna reverse the feed, Miriam, now more than ever.
我们讨论过一百次了  那太危险
We've been through this a hundred times, Catherine. It's too risky.
为什么?  我们有什么可损失的?
Why not? What do we have to lose?
在我做社工时
When I did social work, it was always better...
把孩子带离他本身的环境会更好
...when we took the kids out of their environment.
孩子初入寄养家庭会很害怕
Foster homes can be scary at first...
但最后事情总会好转
...but eventually they see things can be different.
艾华现在就是那个情况
Edward is like that right now.
他处身在一个不健康的环境中
He's living in a world that is not healthy.
- 我们应该带他去别处  - 假设我们依照你的方法做
- Let's show him a different place. - All right. Let's say we do it your way.
把艾华带进你的内心世界
We reverse the feed and we bring Edward into your mind.
他发现被塞进别的世界
Can you imagine his shock when he finds...
肯定会被吓坏的
...he's been thrust into this whole other world?
- 我也经常这么做  - 但你是自愿的
- I do it all the time. - Yes, but you're a willing participant, Catherine.
你知道会发生什么事  但艾华是在昏迷中
You're aware of what's happening. Edward's in a coma.
而且我们还未知道这对你的影响
And besides, we don't know what effect it will have on you.
你已筋疲力竭了
I mean, you're already exhausted.
-  你有没有睡觉?  - 有
- Have you been sleeping? - Yes.
- 还有没有发噩梦?  - 没有
- Any more nightmares? - No.
- 没有  - 那就好了
- No. - Good.
把工作留在这里  别带回家
Leave work here. Don't take it home in this.
嘿  你好啊
Hey, you.
你在找什么?
What are you looking for? Hmm?
想喝牛奶吗?
Want some milk?
艾华
CATHERINE: Edward.
艾华  是你吗?
CATHERINE [THINKING]: Edward, is that you?
你出海时  有没有见到
Edward, were there seals being killed on the beach...
海豹被杀?
...while you were sailing?
别躲  甜心  艾华  是你吗?
Don't hide, sweetie, please? Edward, is that you?
别怕  没有人会伤害你
Don't be afraid. No one will hurt you.
艾华  是你吗?
Edward, is that you?
睡吧
Go to sleep.
爸爸
WOMAN: Daddy!
救命呀
Help"
Somebody, help me!
救命呀
WOMAN: Help me!
- 谢谢你等我  高尔  - 别客气
- Thanks for waiting, Cole. - Teddy Lee, no problem.
联邦密探林西
Special Agent Ramsey.
- 我是高尔  - 早安
- Cole. - Morning.
谁发现她的?
Who found her?
铁路的测量员  今早六时左右
COLE: The surveyor for the railroad, about 6 this morning.
刹车痕跟雷诺裸尸案的一样
Skid marks appear to match the tire tracks from Reno.
似乎撞到栏杆  刮下了一点车漆
And it looks like he scraped the rail, lost some paint too.
车漆已送去化验
It's on its way to the lab already.
尸体被弃置在这边
Dumped the body over there.
漂白水
Bleach.
卫安妮  第七名受害人
RAMSEY: Anne Marie Vicksey. She makes seven.
我的天
Jeez, this stinks.
- 她们全都看来像洋娃娃?  - 是的
- Do they all look like dolls? - TEDDY: Every unfortunate soul.
- 那是什么?  - 颈圈之类
- COLE: What's that? - Some kind of a collar.
- 那是他的手法之一  - 他戴上去的?
- Part of his methodology. - The way he puts it there?
他为她们造的
He makes it for them.
这令他觉得她们属于他
It makes him feel they belong to him.
水位通常都这么低吗?
NOVAK: ls the water always this low?
是的  每年这个时候都是
Yeah, this time of year.
立刻给我验尸报告  还有初步化验报告
Give me a coroner's report right away. Preliminary forensics too.
任何人都不得拖延这宗案件
I don't want anyone dragging their ass on this.
- 工作怎么样?  - 精疲力竭
- So how was work? - Ugh. Exhausting.
我也没主意  珍妮
RAMSEY: I have no idea, Jeannie. For God's sake.
祝你好运  我也爱你  我要挂线了
Good luck with the monster. I love you too. Gotta go.
- 好的  谢谢  拜  - 好吧  拜拜
- JEANNIE [OVER PHONE]: Okay. Thanks. Bye. - All right. Bye-bye.
刚出炉的报告
Hot off the presses.
各位  没有新的消息可报告了
TEDDY: Oh. There's nothing new to report, gentlemen.
精液吻合
A match on his semen.
她肺中的水
Water in her lungs...
含有大量氯气和铁锈
...show high levels of chlorine and rust.
请问这是什么?
What pray tell is this?
他们说发现了狗毛?
They say they found some dog hair?
- 是警犬吗?  - 不  不是警犬
- From a K-9 unit? - No. There was no K-9 unit.
而且卫安妮没有养狗
And Anne Vicksey doesn't own a dog, Teddy.
我想看清楚这根狗毛
I wanna see this.
你想找什么?
What you got, Teddy?
哼
TEDDY: Hmm.
白蚀
Hypomelanosis.
那是什么意思?
And that means?
完全没有黑色素
A complete absence of melanin.
那只狗有白化病
The dog is an albino.
他喜欢那样的动物
He'd love an animal like that.
各位
TEDDY: Gentlemen...
我相信白蚀的狗是很罕见的
...I believe an albino dog is a rare animal indeed.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你不会有事的
You're gonna be okay.
乖乖  对不起
Baby, I'm so sorry.
老天爷  彼得
Jesus Christ, Peter.
我以为你会睡一会  清洁一下吧
Thought you were gonna get some sleep, clean yourself up.
清洁好了
I did.
- 他们在等  - 我预备好了
- They're waiting, you know. - I'm ready.
那么我们走吧
Let's go. Ahem.
我们分两头进行
NOVAK: We're gonna do this two ways.
联络狼狗养殖场
Breeders of German shepherds.
福特代理商
Ford dealers.
调查要彻底  行动要快
I want you to be thorough, and I also want you to be fast.
这个人出动得越来越频密了  今次他只等了六天
This guy's accelerating. He only waited six days this time.
他开始时隔几个月才犯一次案  这有两个可能
When he first started, months could pass. And that means one of two different things.
一  他以为我们蠢得抓不到他
One, he thinks we're stupid and we can't catch him.
二  我相信是这个  他想被捕
Two, which is the one that I believe, he wants to be caught.
留下狗毛太大意了
The dog hair thing is sloppy.
他把卫安妮弃置在水深三寸之处
He leaves Anne Marie Vicksey in three inches of water.
明知我们会发现她
He knew that we'd find her.
有一件事是肯定的
Now, there's one thing I know for certain.
如果我们制止不到他
If we can't stop him...
他自己无法制止自己
...he ain't gonna stop himself.
这张照片可以吗?
Will this be all right?
可以了  谢谢你
Yes, ma'am, that's great. Thank you very much.
她仍然住在家里吗?
She was still, uh, living at home, ma'am?
我们正在找房子
We were looking for apartments.
但他们在结婚前不会搬进去
But they're not moving in together until after the wedding.
茱莉想结婚
Julia wants to be married.
她有没有提及过不寻常的事?
Did she ever mention anything out of the ordinary?
例如最近认识的人
For instance, somebody she recently met...
或是否有人跟踪她?
...or somebody perhaps watching her, following her?
没提过
No.
不好意思
Pardon me.
林西
Ramsey.
如果是你弄错了呢?
WOMAN: What if you made a mistake?
也许不是那个人  也许她很安全
Maybe this isn't the man. Maybe Julia's safe.
他的某些行径
There's certain things that he does...
令我们颇为肯定是他做的
...that, uh, make us pretty positive that this is the man.
去年我丈夫癌症过身了
WOMAN: Last year, I lost my husband to cancer.
他痛得要命  但茱莉总在他身旁
I went through such terrible pain. But Julia, she was always there for me.
什么事  林西?
What's going on, Gordon?
河滨区警方在林峰找到一个狗场
Riverside sheriff found a dog breeder in Woodcrest.
三年前卖出过一只白蚀小狼狗
Three years ago, she had a buyer for an albino shepherd pup.
据运输署纪录  买主开一辆福特
Sheriff checks DMV. Son of a bitch drives a '92 Ford pickup.
- 猜那是什么颜色的  - 水绿色
- Guess what color. - Aqua green.
林西
Ramsey!
- 彼得  - 他在哪里?
- Novak! - Where is he?
爱迪信街
Edison, just east of Lorna Park.
特种部队已监视了那处四十分钟
SWATs had the house under surveillance for about 20 minutes.
史卡莱  没有登记武器  没案底
Carl Rudolph Stargher. No registered weapons, no priors.
狗倒有领牌  叫华伦泰
Got a license for his dog, though. Named him Valentine.
哈
Ha!
你就是凶手吧  是吗  卡莱?
You're the bad man. Aren't you, Carl?
你会吗?
Would you?
我的天
[GRUNTING AND GASPING]
[DISTORTED VOICE SPEAKING]
我的天  醒过来
林西探员  彼得探员
Brock, Agent Ramsey, Agent Novak.
我们已尽快赶来  他们已知情况
We got here as fast as we could. I briefed them on the way over.
现况如何?
Where do we stand?
现在的情况是
Here's the situation.
我在屋顶上派驻了一队人员
We got a high-ground team on the roof...
东面有四名武装队员
...a four-man element to the east.
货车上有破门部队
We got an entry team in the van across from the house...
南面有两人
...a two-man element to the south.
- 你们见到他没有?  - 还没有
- Have you seen him yet? - No.
厨房里有些动静  但看不出是谁
There's been some movement in the kitchen. Can't tell what it is.
- 你认为她在里面吗?  - 当她在吧
- RAMSEY: You think the girl's in there? - NOVAK: We'll proceed assuming that she is.
- 联邦密探  联邦密探  - 快
- AGENT 1: FBI! FBI! - AGENT 2: Go!
别动  杂种
Freeze, motherfucker!
联邦密探
MAN 3: FBI! FBI!
我找到那只狗了
I got the dog!
- 没有人  - 没有人
- Clear. - Clear.
送他去县医院  李德已经在那里
They'll take him to County General. Reid's already there.
一定要用手铐  两个人看守
Make sure he stays cuffed. I want two men on him at all times.
不准李德以外的任何人治理他
I don't want anyone to treat him but Reid.
塞一支探热针入他屁股都不行
Not so much as a thermometer up his ass, understand?
是
Mm.
- 彼得  她不在这里  - 是的
- Peter, she's not here. - Yeah.
你该下来看看
You should, uh, come downstairs.
(漂白水)
(你有病吗?)
(雕刻家)
妈咪
WOMAN: Mommy!
帮我照顾孩子
Please take care of my little baby!
喂?  喂?
Hello? Hello?
求求你  你在吗?  喂?
Please, is there anybody there? Hello?
你听到我说话吗?
Can you hear me?
喂?
Hello?
我没看见你的脸
I didn't see your face.
我没看见
I didn't see...
你的任何一面
...any part of you.
这不是真的
This is not happening to me.
难以置信
I can't believe this is happening.
你们有没有听过惠伦氏症?
Have you ever heard of Whelan's infraction?
是一种精神分裂  很罕见  也很严重
It's a form of schizophrenia. It's very rare, and it's very severe.
精神分裂的人  这些部分会受侵袭
In any schizophrenic, these areas would be affected...
但惠伦氏症的人特别严重和快速
...but in someone with Whelan's, they're hit hard and they're hit fast.
不能给他大量镇静剂或精神药吗?
Can't you load him up with Thorazine or Desoxyn?
普通治疗精神病的药没有用
REID: Normal psychotropics don't work.
病因是病毒在子宫感染神经系统
This thing is caused by a virus that infects the neurological system in utero.
它一直蛰伏  直至有创伤引发
It lays dormant until it's triggered by some kind of trauma.
他的病症可能已出现了一段时间
Most likely, he's exhibited symptoms for some time...
但到今天才真正病发
...but the infraction, or the breach, didn't occur till today.
引发的因素有很多
The triggers can vary.
通常都与水有关  但结果都一样
Uh, usually water-related, but the results don't vary.
他不只是患上紧张症
He's not just catatonic.
他是消失了  就像做梦  而且永远醒不过来一样
He's disappeared. Like having a dream and never waking up.
- 这会维持多久?  - 永远
- For how long? - Oh, forever.
我想我们没提到最重要那点
Lee, I think we might be missing the bigger picture here.
无论他是在何种状态
Now, whatever state that he happens to be in...
仍有一名女子失踪  她叫贺茱莉
...there is a girl that is missing and her name is Julia Hickson...
而他是唯一知道她在哪里的人
...and he is the only one that knows where she is.
他把她们藏在密室里约四十小时
He keeps them in this thing for about 40 hours.
他是在昨晚七时半掳走贺茱莉的
Now, he took Julia Hickson at 7:30 last night.
彼得  你知道我的为人  如果有任何事  任何事
Peter, you know me. If there were anything, anything...
什么?
What?
他给她们食物  水  还有厕所
He provides them with food, drinking water and a toilet.
她们以为只是绑架  不一定会死
Now, she thinks she's been kidnapped, that there's a chance of survival...
但这只是一种折磨
...but it's just a form of torture.
这对他来说是一个洁净仪式  之后再带她们回家
This is a kind of ritual for him, a cleansing before he takes them home...
把受害者造成玩偶  变成玩具
...and turns them into a doll, a toy.
密室是完全自动化的
Now, this thing is fully automated...
除非我们今晚之前找到她
...and unless we find her by tonight...
否则她也会遭遇同一命运
...this will happen to her.
关于这次联合行动
At the request of Mr. Cooperman...
我们联络过你们的董事局
...we've contacted your board of directors.
他们已经批准
And they've given their approval.
艾华的父母也批准了
And so have Edward's parents.
不过决定权仍在你们
But the decision is yours.
亨利?
Henry?
好
Yes.
- 美琳?  - 由嘉芙决定吧
- Miriam? - It's up to Catherine.
她才是要面对真正危险的人
She's the one who'd have to face whatever risks there might be...
她作的任何决定我都会支持
...so I support whatever decision she makes.
- 我可以问你一个问题吗?  - 请便
- Can I ask you something? - Please.
如果他不是昏迷不醒
If he wasn't like this, if he was conscious...
你认为他会说出茱莉的所在吗?
...do you think that he would tell you where she is?
罪犯总是有忏悔的可能的
There's always a chance of a confession. Yeah.
他的行为显示他需要让人知道
And there's things he's done that show a need for disclosure.
只是没有人愿意听
He hasn't had a sympathetic ear.
他想有人听他说话  明白他
He wants someone to listen, to, uh, try and understand him.
我很同情这位女士  这是真的
Look, I feel for this girl, I do...
可是史卡莱可能已不知道真相
...but Stargher may no longer know the truth.
因为
For severe schizophrenics...
严重精神分裂者分不开真假
...there's no discerning between fantasy and reality.
- 他有可能说出真相吗?  - 如果他信任我  是有可能的
- Is it possible? - If he came to trust me, yes...
不过赢取这种信任需要几个月
...but it takes months to earn that kind of trust.
他有可能说出真相吗?
Is it possible?
爸爸?
WOMAN [ON VIDEO]: Daddy?
我是爸爸的乖女
I'm your little baby. Baby...
爸爸
Daddy.
Daddy!
我是你女儿啊
I'm daddy's girl.
他的层级太深了
His levels are too flat.
- 这里怎么了?  - 我们除去了十四个钢环
- MIRIAM: What happened here? - We removed 14 steel rings.
应该让他保持原状的
Should have left him the way he was.
他喜欢吊起自己吧?
He used to suspend himself, didn't he?
是的
Yeah.
精神分裂的人喜欢无重的感觉
They're comforted by the feeling of weightlessness...
就像浮在水中似的
...like floating in water.
各位  这是催化剂
Now this, gentlemen, is the catalyst.
名为神经染色体结合转移系统
The neurological connectic transfer system...
它不单止描绘出内心世界
...not only maps the mind...
还将讯号传送到另一个个体
...it sends the signal to another party.
接收者只需调较到适当的频道
All you need to do is tune in...
调较之后
...but you do much more than tune in.
接收者便变成其内心世界一部分
You become part of the show.
他已经准备好了
MIRIAM: He's ready.
为什么有三个平台?
Why are there three stations?
我们尝试进行联合疗法
We tried joint therapy sessions...
用两个心理学家  但艾华不喜欢
...two shrinks for the price of one, but Edward hated it...
他只肯跟嘉芙说话  她有天份
...and only talked to Catherine. She has a gift.
你肯定要这样做吗?
Are you sure?
我肯定
I'm sure.
好吧
Okay.
反应信号
Response signal.
正在操作
Functioning.
我们在她手中植入了微型晶片
We implanted a touch-sensitive microchip in her hand...
如果她想停止或受不了
...so if she wants to stop the session...
按动晶片  我们便会
...or if it gets too intense, she can give the signal...
将过程中止
...and we abort.
当初我们预备好要实际测试时
When we were ready for practical testing...
我们见过
...Miriam and I auditioned...
很多优秀儿童心理学家
...some of the best child therapists in the country.
他们只是观察  然后汇报
And all they did was observe and report, nothing more.
嘉芙经验最浅  但备受推崇
HENRY: Catherine was the least experienced, but she came so highly recommended...
我们决定姑且让她一试
...that we decided, what the hell, we'll give her a shot...
我们立刻便发现她与众不同
...and immediately, we could tell she was different.
你不是人类  你不该待在我的房子里
MAN: You're not human. You don't lie in my house.
你是动物  这是我的房子
You're an animal! This is my house.
嘿
Hey!
嘿  你好啊
Hey, you.
你喜欢人轻拍你吧  对吗?
Yeah, you like that, don't you?
你的名字是卡莱吗?
Is your name Carl?
我认识一个男孩也有马
You know, I know another little boy with a horse.
叫艾华  那孩子叫艾华  不是那只马
His name's Edward. I mean the boy, not the horse.
有什么不妥?
What's wrong?
他杀死的人
His victims.
你从哪里来的?
Where do you come from?
- 喂  - 各位  她回来了
- Yeah. - HENRY [OVER PHONE]: Gentlemen, she's back.
我立刻过来
I'll be right there.
没事了  别怕  嘉芙
MIRIAM: All right. Come on, Catherine.
她的旅程很特别
HENRY: She's had quite a journey.
跟以往不同
Unlike anything we've ever seen before.
- 那么她接触到他了?  - 是的
- So she's made contact? - Oh, yes.
她进入了他内心深处  太深了
She's gone very deep into his world. At times too far.
- 很冷  - 那很危险
- It's cold. - HENRY: That can be dangerous.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
她若相信史卡莱的世界是真的
Well, if she came to believe that Stargher's world is real...
她的心便会说服她的身体
...then theoretically, her mind could convince her body...
在那里  发生在她身上的事
...that anything that was done to it there...
便是真的
...is actually done.
就像坊间迷信  如果你在梦中梦见自己死去
It's like the old wives' tale where you die in your dream...
那你真的会在现实中死亡
...you die in real life.
提高这里的温度可以吗?
Henry, could you raise the temperature in here?
- 靳医生?  - 请你等一等
- Dr. Kent? - MIRIAM: Just a moment, please.
请问我可以和你谈谈吗?
Can I come in there and speak with her?
你要有耐性
We have to be patient.
看看她  昏昏欲睡  让她醒过来
I mean, look at her. She's drowsy. Let her wake up.
我们没有很多时间  你明白吗?
We don't have a lot of time. Do you understand that?
我们在天上的父
Our Father, who art in heaven...
愿人都尊你的名为圣
...hallowed be thy name.
天国福音降临于世
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done, on earth as it is in heaven.
我有没有打扰你们?
NOVAK: Am I interrupting anything?
我可以坐下来吗?
Is it okay if I...?
他知道你来了  是吗?
He knows you're here, doesn't he?
我朋友李德医生说
My friend, uh, Dr. Reid, said...
这么小的孩子  罹患精神分裂
...that it's very unusual, uh, schizophrenia that is...
- 是很罕见的  - 医生一般会以为是自闭症
- ...in a child that's this young. - They usually think it's autism.
你得明白他的身体没有问题
What you have to understand is there's nothing wrong with his body.
瘫痪的是他一部分的心智
What's paralyzed is a part of his mind.
心智受病毒侵害  以致他不能动
It's so damaged by the virus he can't even will himself to move.
你认为你可以改变现状吗?
You think you can change that?
你相信你内心有一部分
Do you believe there's a part of yourself...
是你永远不会示人的吗?
...that you don't show anybody?
我想人人都有那一部分
I think everybody has that side of themselves.
在实验中  我进入别人的心灵时
During a session, when I'm inside...
我便见到这一部分
...I get to see those things.
我感觉到它们
I feel them.
在卡莱的内心  我感觉到一种我不想再有的感觉
With Stargher, I felt things I never wanna feel again.
他甚至不再是史卡莱
He's not even Carl Stargher anymore.
他是一个理想化了的自己  是一个变态王国的王帝
He's this idealized version of himself, a king in a very, very twisted kingdom.
在那里他可以尽情堕落
It's the place for him to indulge every...
我不想在这儿谈这些事
You know, I don't wanna talk about this in here.
我永远做不到你所做的
I could never do what you do...
全心全意去了解这样的心灵
...devote myself to understanding a mind like that.
我不认为我终会了解他的内心
I don't think we'll ever be able to understand a mind like that.
可是你尝试  那是你的工作
But you try. That's your job.
我想是吧
I guess so.
- 你不喜欢你的工作吗?  - 比起上一份工作  我较喜欢这份
- You don't like what you do? - I like it better than my old job.
我以前是律师  当检察官
Used to be an attorney. I was a prosecutor.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
我有宗案件  一个小女孩遭非礼
I had a case, uh, where this little girl was molested.
只因一件小证物被污染了
And because of this one tiny piece of evidence...
他获无罪释放
...that was tainted, he walked.
贾卓士  他无罪释放
Charles Gish walked away.
我却无能为力
Nothing I could do about it.
他获释的那天晚上
The night after he was released...
玛姬的父母回到家
...Margaret's parents came home.
这是那小女孩的名字  单玛姬
That was the little girl's name, Margaret Sims.
他们发现贾卓士坐在客厅中
And they found Charles Gish sitting in their living room.
他在看电视
He was watching television...
玛姬坐在他身旁
...and Margaret was sitting next to him...
他把她从中切开两半
...and he had cut her open right down the middle.
父母还在冰箱中发现玛姬的心脏
And the parents found Margaret's heart in the freezer.
卓士觉得他们可能想保存它留念
Charles figured they'd probably wanna keep it.
之后我便辞了职  加入联邦密探
After that, I left the DA and joined the FBI.
我想尝试捉拿他们
Figured I'd just try to catch them.
直到如今
Till now.
是的
Yeah.
我告诉你  史卡莱不再是史卡莱了
You know, I started to tell you that Stargher really isn't Stargher anymore.
那是真的  也是假的
Well, that's true, and it's not.
主要的部分仍是那恐怖的东西
The dominant side is still this horrible thing...
- 但也有正面的部分  - 正面的部分?
- ...but there's a positive side that-- - Positive side?
他视自己为儿童的那部分
Well, the way he sees himself as a child.
- 但那个是他吗?  - 儿童史卡莱接触我
- But isn't that him? - The boy Stargher made contact.
他对我好奇
He's curious about me.
我接近那孩子  或可知道茱莉下落
If I could reach the boy, then maybe he'd tell me about Julia.
贾卓士后来怎样?
What ever happened to Charles Gish?
他因为精神病而逃过谋杀罪
Old Charlie beat the murder rap because, uh, he was insane when he killed Margaret.
他的律师把陪审团说得帖帖服服
His attorney, uh, milked the jury for all they were worth.
他说贾卓士自小遭到性侵犯  才令他走上这条路
Said that a life of sexual abuse drove him to do these things...
他妈的  什么鬼话连篇
...and, you know, what ever the fuck. All that same old bullshit. Heh.
那为什么是鬼话?
Why is that bullshit?
我相信一个孩子可以经历
I believe a child can experience...
比贾卓士糟一百倍的性侵犯
...a hundred times worse the abuse than what Gish went through...
但仍然会长大  成为一个
...and still grow up to be somebody that would never, ever...
永远永远不会伤害别人的人
...ever hurt another living being.
你肯定吗?
And you're sure of that?
是的
Yes, I am.
我肯定
I'm sure of that.
你去了哪里?
Hey, where the hell you been?
我一直在这里
I've been right here.
下次先告诉我好吗?
Well, next time tell me, okay?
我不想打扰你
I didn't wanna disturb you. You looked so cute.
你睡相那么可爱
You're all sleeping when you get that look on you.
你的同事想知道拿史卡莱怎么办
Your colleagues wanna know what to do with, uh, Stargher.
叫他们帮他准备好吧  我立刻到
Tell them to prep him. I'll be right there.
谢谢你  嘉芙
Thank you, Catherine.
史卡莱有没有宠物?  猫狗之类?
Stargher have any pets? You know, cats, dogs...
你真乖啊  对吗  华伦泰?
Yeah, you're a good boy, aren't you, Valentine?
- 那会有帮助吗?  - 对  在潜意识的层面
- That's supposed to help? - On a subconscious level, yes.
任何对卡莱有意义  令他开心的事物
Anything that was special to Stargher, gave him pleasure...
都应该会令他较易接近
...should make him more accessible...
- 平静的状态  - 平静?
...more peaceful. - Peaceful?
那样就可以了
MIRIAM: That's enough, then.
- 警探  - 医生
- MIRIAM: Mr. Novak. - Doctor.
- 谢谢  - 开始吧
- Thank you. - You got it.
第二回合
Round two.
亨利  这不好笑
CATHERINE: Henry, not funny.
- 怎么啦?  - 一点也不好笑  亨利
- What's happening? - CATHERINE: Not funny, Henry.
- 嘉芙  - 别这样  不要再玩了
- HENRY: Catherine. - Come on, stop playing around.
我没开玩笑  这是电力故障
HENRY: I'm not. It's a power problem.
我们被锁在外面了
We're locked out, Catherine.
你得检查一下断路器
I need you to check the circuit breaker.
你去检查电路六至十二
I want you to check circuits six through 12.
- 快呀  起来  - 嗯哼
- Come on. Get up. - CATHERINE: Mm-hm.
六至十二
HENRY: Six through 12.
我已经进去了
I'm already in.
她说什么?
What did she say?
华伦泰
Valentine.
CATHERINE: Valentine.
过来  乖
Come here, boy.
华伦泰
Valentine.
你可以带我去见卡莱吗?
Can you take me to Carl?
需要帮忙吗?
Need some help?
我有份礼物给你
I've got a present for you.
如果你需要我
If you need me...
或者你觉得我在附近  却找不到我
...or if you feel like I'm around, but you can't find me, just...
只要用这个反射光线就行
Shine it like this.
拿去吧
Go ahead, take it.
喜欢吗?
You like it?
- 卡莱?  - 什么事?
- CARL'S FATHER: Carl? - What's the matter?
有什么不妥?
What? What's wrong?
这里发生什么事?  那碟子是自己破的吗?
CARL'S FATHER: What happened over here? Just broke all by itself.
- 是不是你打破的?  - 是我打破的
- Did you break that plate? - CATHERINE: I broke the plate.
- 碟子是不是你打破的?  以为我很多钱吗? - 是我打破的
- Did you break that plate? - I broke the plate.
我们把它们全打破吧  怎么样?
Well, hey. Let's break them all, how about that?
他妈的  你这个大话精!
You little fucking liar!
该把你像发育不全的畜牲般淹死
I should've drowned you like the runt of the litter.
在我家不准说谎  这是我的家
You don't lie in my house. This is my house!
不是我给他的
[WOMAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
洋娃娃是女孩的  不能给男孩玩
CARL'S FATHER: A doll? Those are for girls, you dumb whore.
- 只是玩具而已  - 闭嘴  八婆
- WOMAN: It's just a toy. - CARL'S FATHER: Shut up!
你不是他亲生妈妈  她不是你妈妈
You're not his mother! She's not your mother.
你妈妈抛弃了我们  你要记住
She left us, Carl. Remember that.
看到了吗?  看到了吗?
See that? See that?
这里是
That is...
邪恶之地
...a place of evil.
混蛋
What the fucking cripes?
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
这他妈的是什么?  过来
What the fuck is this? Get back, get over here!
玩洋娃娃?  你这个小基佬
Playing with dolls? You little faggot!
你是什么?  女人吗?
What are you, some kind of a woman? Get up!
- 可是  爸  啊  - 他妈的
- CARL: But, Dad-- Aah! - CARL'S FATHER: Damn it.
你想哭吗?
You want something to cry about?
给你一个哭的理由吧  女人
I'll give you something to cry about, woman!
- 啊  - 女人型
- CARL: Aah! - Mama's boy!
我养的不是基佬!
I didn't raise no faggot!
天啦
Christ.
不准再哭  你想像女人般熨衣服吗?
Stop your crying. You wanna iron like a woman?
- 让我教你怎样像女人般熨衣服吧  - 不
- Let me show you how to iron. - CATHERINE: No!
救命
WOMAN: Help me.
她
CARL: She...
她是我的第一个
She was my first.
我弄得一塌糊涂
And I made such a mess.
不知道自己在干什么
Didn't know what I was doing.
你为什么会在这里?
Why are you here?
不要说谎
Don't lie.
- 我来帮你的  - 你撒谎
- I came to help you. - You're lying.
婊子  贱人
Bitch. Whore.
烂屄
Cunt!
你说话就像你爸爸
You sound like your father.
他一文不值  他一文不值
[DISTORTED VOICE] He was nothing. He is nothing.
谁叫你那么说的?
Who told you to say that?
你记得他第一次跟你说话吗?
Do you remember the first time he talked to you?
你当时在水中吗?  也许你在游泳
Were you in water? Maybe you went swimming.
那是我的浸礼
It was my baptism.
我爸爸  他把我按入水底
My father, he pushed me under.
我当时几乎心脏病发
I think I had some kind of seizure.
我以为我要淹死了  大家只是袖手旁观
I think I was drowning, and everybody just looked at me.
没有人救我  没有人
Nobody helped me. Nobody.
除了他
Except him.
我爸爸
My father...
那晚带我回家  打断了我三条肋骨
...he took me home that night and he broke three of my ribs...
打裂了我的下颚
...and fractured my jaw.
当时我只有六岁
I was 6 years old.
卡莱
Carl.
你爸爸对你的行为是邪恶的
What your father did to you is evil.
是错的
What he did to you was wrong.
- 他像对待死物似的对待你  - 不
- He treated you like a thing. - No.
他比我更强大
He was more powerful than me.
不对  没有人应该受到那种对待的
No. No one should be treated like that.
是吗?
Is that right?
那么你的世界是怎样的?
In what world do you live in?
- 卡莱  贺茱莉在哪里?  - 不
- Carl, where is Julia Hickson? - No.
不准提名字
No names.
No names!
她在哪里?
Where is she?
我了解你  卡莱  你想告诉我的
I know you, Carl. You wanna tell me.
你了解我?
[IN DISTORTED VOICE] You know me?
你知道我是谁吗?
You know who I am?
她在哪里?
Where is she?
茱莉在哪里?
Where's Julia?
茱莉在哪里  卡莱?
Where's Julia, Carl?
- 美琳  - 嗯哼?
- Miriam. - Mm-hm?
那一定有问题
That can't be right.
开到最大
MIRIAM: Danger pulse.
- 没有变化  - 天呀
- No change. - Christ.
- 紧急中止好吗?  - 不
- What about emergency cessation? - No.
中断输送器  关闭接收仪
Gradually terminate the feed, disable the receptors--
这会造成严重震荡的  关上那个
It could lead to massive shock. Could you please shut that thing off?
发生什么事?
What's going on?
我跟你说过的那假设情况
HENRY: That hypothetical situation I told you about.
- 现在成真了  - 你不能中止它吗?
- It's happening. - NOVAK: Can't you stop it?
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
- 你以前中止过的  - 对  但情况不同  那是艾华
- You stopped it before-- - Yes, that was different. That was Edward.
史的内心是陌生世界  她迷失了
With Stargher, his mind is unfamiliar territory and she's lost.
- 她以为这是真的  - 我们有什么可以做的?
- She thinks this is real. - NOVAK: Anything we can do?
我们做什么都可能令情况更坏
Whatever we do runs the risk of making things worse for her.
好极了  那么她就在某处迷失了
NOVAK: Worse. That's great. So she's lost somewhere?
亨利
Henry.
- 不行  不行  - 什么不行?
- No.No. - No, what?
我需要你在这里
I need you here.
他妈的停止  停止  停止
Fucking stop! Stop! Stop!
他妈的放我出去
Let me the fuck out!
我不想再困在这里了
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
他妈的放我出去  放我出去
Let me the fuck out. Let me out!
放我出去  你这个变态贱人
Get me out, you sick fuck!
你去死吧  放我出去
Fuck you! Let me out.
救自己  救自己  茱莉
Do something. Do something to end this.
救自己
Do some-- Do something.
我觉得全身像爬满虫似的
I got bugs crawling all over my body.
感觉会越来越差
It gets worse.
你对这个完全没有准备
You're completely unprepared for this.
- 靳医生  这件事我们已讨论过了  - 对  但我试过这个程序
- Dr. Kent, we've been over all this. - Yes, but I've been through the process.
她也试过这个程序  那没有关系
She went through the process too and it didn't matter.
你不认识他
You don't know him.
好吧
Okay.
祝你好运
Be lucky.
来吧
Come on, guys.
预备好了吗?
Ready?
彼得  最初几分钟
Uh, Peter, the first few minutes...
你会很迷失
...will be very disorienting.
记着要保持镇定  集中精神
Remember to stay calm and focused.
直觉在这阶段很重要  信任直觉
Instincts play a very important part here, so trust them.
- 要开始了  - 好
- We have to go. - Yeah. All right.
彼得  你看过她的档案
Peter, you've read her file.
对她说一些很个人的事
Hit her with something personal.
记着  彼得  这不是真实的
And remember, Peter, it's not real.
搞什么鬼?
What the fuck?
见到我儿子吗?
Have you seen him? My boy? My little one?
- 他爸爸带走了他  - 他是我那个洞屙出来的  了不起啊
- His father took him from me. - I spit him out my hole. Big deal.
- 并不意味着我不在乎他  - 我的孩子讨厌死了  他没有灵魂
- Don't mean I can't take care of him. - My child's an abomination. He has no soul.
好吧
Okay.
嘉芙
Catherine.
是你吗?  你没事吧?
Is that you? You all right?
嘉芙
Catherine.
- 彼得  - 听我说
- CATHERINE [THINKING]: Peter. - Listen to me.
可怜的彼得
Poor Peter.
这不是真实的
This isn't real.
爸爸有没有做坏事啊?
CATHERINE: Did daddy do a bad thing?
嘉芙  求求你听我说
NOVAK [THINKING]: Catherine, please listen to me.
洛彼得
CATHERINE: Peter Novak.
我是联邦密探
NOVAK: I Work With the FBI.
我们来此找贺茱莉
I'm here to find Julia Hickson.
别怕
CATHERINE: Don't be scared.
嘉芙  看看你手上的东西
This isn't real.
你记得吗?
You remember that?
在你手上你可以按动的那东西?
嘉芙  听我说
Catherine, listen to me.
嘉芙  我们是来找...
Catherine.
嘉芙
嘉芙  你得试着记起来
Catherine, you gotta try to remember.
你记得艾华吗?
Do you remember Edward?
嘉芙
Catherine.
跟我说句话
Talk to me for a sec.
卑鄙小人
Naughty worm.
你去死吧  狗杂种
Fuck you! Fuck you, motherfucker!
嘉芙  他妈的快醒过来
Catherine, wake the fuck up now!
母马吃燕麦  雌鹿吃燕麦
[MUSIC BOX PLAYING AND CARL HUMMING]
小绵羊吃常春藤
小山羊也吃常春藤
你会吃吗?
[SINGS INDISTINCTLY]
嘉芙
Catherine!
在你念大学时
When you were in college...
你弟弟发生车祸
...your baby brother had a car accident!
他昏迷了六个月才去世
He was in a coma for six months before he died!
很抱歉我要提起这件事
And I'm sorry for saying that!
但你得醒过来啊
But you gotta wake up!
天啊
God!
这不是真实的
It's not real.
这不是真的
这不是真实的  不是真实的
"It's not real! It's not real! Not real!
不是真实的
Not real! Not real!"
彼得
Peter.
- 没事了  - 他妈的发生了什么事?
- It's okay. - What the fuck happened?
我们在哪里?
Where are we?
噢  天呐
CATHERINE: Oh, my God.
这就是他囚禁她的地方吗?
Is this where he keeps them?
卡莱  没事了
Carl. Oh, it's okay.
茱莉
NOVAK: Julia.
不要怕
CATHERINE: Don't be scared.
我永远不会伤害你的  我是你的朋友
I would never hurt you. I'm your friend.
彼得也是朋友
And Peter, he's a friend too.
你知道这地方在地图上的哪里吗?
Do you know where this place is? Like on a map?
嗯
Mm.
我真为你骄傲
CATHERINE: I am so proud of you.
(雕刻家)
即使彼得找不到茱莉
Even if Peter doesn't find Julia...
- 我也答应我会回来帮你  - 嘉芙
- ...I promise I will come back and help you. - Catherine!
嘉芙
Catherine!
- 你干什么?  - 我们走吧
- What are you doing? - Let's go.
- 卡莱  - 我见到她  我知道她下落了  走吧
- Carl. - I saw her. I know how to find Julia.
- 我不可以把他留在这里  - 他妈的  嘉芙  我们走吧
- I just can't leave him here! - Goddamn it, Catherine, let's go!
- 卡莱  - 我知道怎样找她了
- CATHERINE: Carl! - I know how to find her.
- 不  卡莱  - 我们一定要回去  没时间了
- No! Carl. - We gotta go back. We're running out of time.
不  我们不可以离开他  回去
CATHERINE: No!
- 我们快走吧  求求你  - 我会回来找你的  卡莱
- NOVAK: Let's go back! Please! - I'll come back for you, Carl!
- 我发誓我一定会回来的  - 嘉芙  我们现在就要走了
- I promise I'll come back! - NOVAK: Catherine, we gotta go now!
- 他回来了 - 嘉芙怎么样?
- RAMSEY: That means he's back. - MIRIAM: How's Catherine?
慢慢来  彼得
Take it easy, Peter.
她没事吧?
Is she okay?
放松点  彼得  慢慢呼吸
Take it easy, Peter. Just breathe.
- 她没事吗  - 是的  我想她没事
- Is she okay? - Yeah, I think she is.
他妈的  你能帮我脱掉这个吗?
Can you get me out of this fucking suit?
我接个电话
Let me get this.
- 我是高尔  - 高尔  我是彼得
- Yeah, Cole here. - Cole, it's Novak.
情况怎么样?
Yeah, what's up?
下去地窖  史卡莱的工作室
I want you to go down to the basement...
你在那里打给我
...at Stargher's workplace and call me when you get down there.
- 他们还在调查  - 别理他妈的调查
- They haven't finished the grid. - Fuck the grid.
- 去那里打给我  - 你没事吧?
- Call me when you get there. - RAMSEY: You okay?
- 没事  - 想告诉我发生什么事吗?
- I'm fine. - What happened in there?
- 妈的  - 你痛吗?
- Oh, fuck. - You in pain?
- 发生什么事?  - 他妈的  我见到她了
- What happened, Peter? - Fuck. I saw her.
- 你见到谁?  - 我知道去哪里找她
- Who? - I know where to find her.
- 谁?  - 茱莉  我知道她在哪里  我见到她
- Who? - Julia. I know where to find her.
你为什么不让靳医生看你一下?
Okay. Why don't you come and, uh, let Dr. Kent have a look at you?
彼得?
Pete?
- 高尔?  - 我是高尔
- Cole? - Yeah, this is Cole. Uh...
我下来这里干嘛?
Now, what am I doing down here?
那张他用的铁床  上面有座吊车
That machine that he uses, there's a hoist.
我想让你
I want you to look for a, uh, plaque...
找一块金属板  上面有商标的
...or a metal plate with some sort of logo on it.
我找到了
Yeah, I got it.
写着雕刻家工业用品
Uh, it's Carver industrial equipment...
地址是加洲贝加士菲市
...in, uh, Bakersfield, California.
我要你尽量找出
Okay. I want you to find out every goddamn thing...
那机器的资料
...that you can about that machine.
用家  卖家  买家
Who used it, who sold it, who bought it.
尽量找
Just find out everything you can.
我待会在直升机打给你
I'm gonna call you from the chopper in about 20 minutes.
让我看看  很好
MIRIAM: All right, let me have a look. Good.
很好
That's good.
- 那联邦密探走了  - 什么?
- HENRY: The FBI has left the building. - What?
我还没检查彼得啊
I haven't had a chance to clear Novak!
你想我怎样?
HENRY: What did you expect me to do?
- 我无法阻止他  - 行了
- HENRY: There's no way I could stop him. - CATHERINE: Go.
- 去检查他吧  我没事  - 你肯定?  让我看看
- I'm okay. Mm-hm. - Are you sure? Let me have a look.
拜托
Come on.
好吧
Okay.
- 好啦  - 好的
- All right. - Okay.
很好
Okay.
说话啊
RAMSEY: Peter, just talk to me.
若那是你的幻觉怎么办?
What if your mind is playing tricks on you?
注射了那么多药  那可能是幻觉
They shot you full of drugs, Peter. Who knows if what you saw is real?
嘉芙?
Catherine?
嘉芙  开门
Catherine, open this door.
嘉芙
Catherine.
- 我发誓  - 你在干什么?
- CATHERINE: I promise... - HENRY: What are you doing?
- 我要帮你  - 不
- ...I'm gonna help you. HENRY: No.
别摧毁你的事业
Do not jeopardize your career.
这是未经批准的程序  你知道的
You're not authorized to be here, you know that.
这很危险  你为什么要这样做?
It's dangerous. What are you doing?
(不准进入)
- 美琳  - 她在干什么?
- HENRY: Miriam. - What's she doing?
- 你知道她在干什么的  - 我的天
- You know what she's doing. - MIRIAM: For Christ's sake.
嘉芙  天呀
Catherine! Jesus.
她更改了密码  你进不去的
HENRY: She's changed the codes. You can't get in.
怎么回事
What happened?
- 她逆转了输送器  - 什么意思?
- She reversed the feeds. - RAMSEY: What does that mean?
那程序本来是让她进入他内心的
The process is intended for her to go into his mind.
但现在她要将他带进她的内心
But instead, she's bringing him into hers.
不会吧
Come on!
我答应过会回来帮你的
I promised I'd come back and help you.
看  我一定会遵守诺言
See, I always keep my promises.
我可以留在这里吗?  跟你一起?
Can I stay here with you?
不  不  甜心  对不起  那样做是不行的
No, honey, I'm sorry. It doesn't work that way.
我没有办法
There's nothing I can do about that.
有的
CARL [IN ADULT VOICE]: Yes, there is.
在我还是孩子的时候
When I was a little boy...
我发现了一只小鸟
...I found this bird.
它受伤了
And he was injured...
断了一条腿或什么的
...had a broken leg or something.
我爸爸知道了这件事
Well, my father found out that I had it.
我知他一定会对它做出可怕的事
And I knew that he would do something horrible to it.
那只是时间问题而已
It was just a matter of time.
所以我在洗碗盆中淹死了它
So I took it to the sink and I held it under.
那对它来说还好一点
It was better for the bird.
我救了它
I saved him.
我不能那样做  卡莱
I can't do that, Carl.
我不会那样做
I won't.
不要紧的
It doesn't matter.
他找到我了
He found me.
他总会找到我的
He always finds me.
洛探员  请通话
Agent Novak? Go ahead.
- 高尔?  - 我是高尔  听着
- Cole? - COLE: Yeah, Novak, listen to this.
吊车卖了给一个姓斑的人
The hoist was sold to a guy named Bainbridge...
他想在迪兰卢附近开一间机器厂
...who tried to build a machine works out near Delano.
他后来破产  州政府接管了厂房
Bainbridge ends up in bankruptcy court and the state winds up with the land.
猜猜州政府雇了谁去封闭厂房
And guess who they hire to seal the place up.
- 你在开玩笑  - 不  我不喜欢开玩笑
- Oh, you're fucking kidding me. - No. I'm not the kidding type.
是史卡莱
Carl Rudolph Stargher.
- 那在哪里?  - 九十九号公路十号出口
- Where's the land? - Exit 10, off Highway 99.
- 我们立即出发  - 我知道在哪里
- We're on our way now. - Got it. I know where that is.
救命
Help! Help me!
是这儿了
PILOT: This is the area.
我的世界  我的规则
CATHERINE [THINKING]: My world, my rules.
下手吧
Do it.
这不是真实的
It's not real.
我的天  天呀
Me-god boy-
天呀  我的天
Boy me-god.
你无法杀死我的
You cannot kill me.
宝贝  没事的
It's okay.
救我
Save me.
留在这里跟我一起吧
You can stay here with me.
嘿
Hey. Hey!
没事了
Hey! It's okay.
没事了  你要离玻璃远一点
It's okay. It's okay. You've gotta back away.
游去后面  去后面  去后面  茱莉
Swim to the back. Back away! Back up from here. Back up!
亨利
Henry.
没事的
It's okay.
没事了
Are you okay? You okay?
你没有事了  你安全了  没事了
You're okay. You're okay. Hey. Hey. You're okay.
- 林西探员?  - 我是林西
- MAN [OVER RADIO]: Agent Ramsey? - Yeah, Ramsey.
她来了
MAN: She's here.
好  让她进来
RAMSEY: Okay, let her through.
外面有人找你
Somebody outside for you.
她来干嘛?
What is she doing here?
她想看看他的家
Said she wanted to see his home.
那真奇怪
NOVAK: It's pretty strange.
她还养着他的狗
She's keeping his dog.
真他妈的奇怪
Pretty fucking strange is par for the course.
我几乎认不出你
I almost didn't recognize you.
你何时恢复平民身份?
How long do you get to be a civilian?
几星期
A couple weeks...
待案件结束后  再看看怎样
...until after the inquiry and see what happens.
林西告诉我  你想...
Ramsey told me you were thinking of, uh...
那个叫什么?
What do you call that thing?
- 逆转  - 逆转
- Reversal? - Reversal.
- 跟那个在协助的孩子吗?  - 是的  他叫艾华
- With the, uh, kid you were working with? - Yeah. Edward.
艾华
Edward.
你肯定你想这么做吗?
Are you sure you wanna do that?
绝对肯定
Absolutely.
你不担心会发生什么事吗?
You're not worried about what might happen?
我永远不会做伤害艾华的事
I would never do anything to hurt Edward.
我不是担心他
It wasn't him I was worried about.
你呢?  你好吗?
What about you? How are you?
我不大肯定
I'm not sure. I...
我记得零零碎碎的片断
I kind of remember pieces of everything.
据联邦调查局所称
According to the FBI, um...
你们给我注射了影响思想的药物
...you guys put me on some drug-fueled mind-bender...
令我想起一个我已有的记忆
...which then, uh, triggered a memory I already had...
据官方纪录
...and officially we found Julia Hickson...
我用传统方法破案
...through good old-fashioned detective work.
我想我该说再见了
I guess this is hello and goodbye, then.
我想是的
I guess so.
感谢一切  嘉芙
Thanks for everything, Catherine.
保重
- Be safe. - All right.
片名: 入 侵 脑 细 胞
港译: 移 魂 追 凶
台译: 死 亡 空 间